
> content-and-level-design@9.0.0 test
> node --test tests/*.test.js

✔ four district art profiles carry unique palette, use and silhouette rules (1.9869ms)
✔ district mixing is normalized and continuous across both axes (0.9743ms)
✔ skyline peaks in downtown and preserves low docks and industrial hierarchy (0.4556ms)
✔ facade palette, material variation and window family reproduce exactly (2.6302ms)
✔ all silhouette sections fit their parcel and the final roof remains centered (4.263ms)
✔ fictional signs have deterministic names and a strictly bounded catalogue (22.5827ms)
✔ V3 windows offer four colors while retaining the historical window API (7.2837ms)
✔ distance bands and budgets are nested from LOW to HIGH (1.1275ms)
✔ prop LOD hides complete props without changing transforms or colors (2.561ms)
✔ graphics changes do not modify generated identities (387.9045ms)
✔ street props use repeatable recipes clear of existing solid envelopes (281.1939ms)
✔ decorations unload, restore art metadata and reproduce exact instance data (220.3326ms)
✔ material count is bounded and all mineral surfaces share procedural shader variants (153.486ms)
✔ fixed instance pool is reused and enforces its hard limit (1.3337ms)
✔ fog has continuous district transitions, altitude thinning and rain thickening (0.4754ms)
✔ rain perception varies smoothly and is reduced for driving (0.2013ms)
✔ rain splash pool is bounded, profile controlled and disabled with rain (7.4883ms)
✔ rare storms repeat on the seed, never fire every minute, and respect pause (1.2421ms)
✔ storm toggle suppresses flash and pending thunder (0.2234ms)
✔ new visual options round trip and older saves receive harmless defaults (0.4764ms)
✔ AUTO reduces art gradually without changing seed or buffers (110.2951ms)
✔ far windows replace detailed panes and reduce the drawn instance count (126.3599ms)
✔ streaming created after LOW retains the full HIGH decoration allocation (99.9995ms)
✔ offset wings have matching physical volumes rather than centered phantom walls (105.0834ms)
✔ shader warmup restores lights, target and interaction owners (95.9578ms)
✔ shader warmup restores lights, target and interaction owners after failure (100.2254ms)
✔ authored locations, objectives, road widths and rooftop chain are physically valid (82.5095ms)
✔ main mission identities and positions stay fixed across secondary seeds (4.3813ms)
✔ campaign prerequisites cannot be bypassed by starting a locked mission (1.8069ms)
✔ all main routes have distinct playable access objectives (1.2513ms)
✔ each mission walkthrough resumes every checkpoint and completes once (2.9213ms)
✔ all seven campaign missions complete, reward and unlock their successor (2.9781ms)
✔ side replay never grants duplicate points or lore (5.5795ms)
✔ objective evidence requires the right domain, action and traversal (1.2847ms)
✔ real inspect interaction advances the active objective only in its interior (8.6477ms)
✔ checkpoint restart retains progress; mission restart returns to the beginning (9.1148ms)
✔ KO returns to the last authored checkpoint without losing discoveries (2.3667ms)
✔ content pause freezes objective and radio timers (3.1779ms)
✔ Exploration suspends story and requires opt-in for discoveries (2.3738ms)
✔ undiscovered secrets and lore never appear as direct map markers (2.7488ms)
✔ nearby secret is collected through real interaction and saved (2.6541ms)
✔ fast travel requires discovery and rejects pursuit, combat and active missions (9.8536ms)
✔ safe point travel prepares its chunk and places a grounded destination (3.1629ms)
✔ fast travel from a moving vehicle exits cleanly and parks it (3.919ms)
✔ six upgrades enforce point costs, bounds and no duplicate purchase (1.2211ms)
✔ upgrade restore cannot spend more than earned or stack repeated bonuses (1.1358ms)
✔ V1 migration preserves player, vehicle, settings and historical progress (1.5077ms)
✔ runtime save round trip retains checkpoint, lore, safe points and upgrades (19.9426ms)
✔ new game removes authored progression but retains user options (4.1982ms)
✔ malformed content is bounded and multiple active missions normalize to one (4.6725ms)
✔ radio queue is bounded, pauses and releases its current line (0.9164ms)
✔ world events are rare, singular, pause aware and restore rain (0.7848ms)
✔ content decoration buffers stay bounded through zones and profiles (9.4768ms)
✔ mission encounters reuse the existing enemy pool and clear on restart (5.9614ms)
✔ grapple ray selects only marked points inside configurable range (2.634ms)
✔ grapple pull and released momentum are identical at 30/60/120 FPS (29.259ms)
✔ grapple cannot select through a wall or pull through a newly blocking wall (4.0956ms)
✔ grapple cancellation releases bounded velocity and permits reuse after cooldown (3.1962ms)
✔ glide reduces descent, advances and exits when Space is released (10.586ms)
✔ glide is excluded on ground, inside rooms and during ladder travel (2.6623ms)
✔ glide trajectory is independent of render frequency (12.2902ms)
✔ momentum strictly bounds horizontal and vertical velocities (1.6547ms)
✔ dodge has a bounded duration/distance, cooldown and respects walls (2.6731ms)
✔ crime site generation is deterministic, chunk-based and offers alternate approaches (15.197ms)
✔ crime spawning avoids the player, honors budgets and recycles resolved events (17.009ms)
✔ mission activation is exclusive and reach/roof/inspect/enter objectives complete (0.529ms)
✔ observation requires sustained aim; neutralization requires a real disabled group (0.6019ms)
✔ missions fail on expiration or removal of their event (0.3363ms)
✔ enemy vision respects cone, height, occlusion and a small rain penalty (2.1061ms)
✔ enemy transitions from suspicion to alert, search and patrol; disabled is terminal (0.4578ms)
✔ noise is bounded, expires, respects range and is slightly masked by rain (0.6405ms)
✔ hearing creates suspicion without immediately alerting the enemy (0.2931ms)
✔ takedown requires short distance, rear approach, no wall and non-alert enemy (1.2739ms)
✔ combat takes three hits, enforces cooldown, range and line of sight (2.0151ms)
✔ health clamps damage, saves safe point and respawns once after a fixed delay (0.6803ms)
✔ scanner has a limited duration, radius and cooldown and reveals nothing when disabled (0.8287ms)
✔ AI perception is staggered to at most two vision rays per simulation tick (6.0102ms)
✔ exploration/vigilante switch enables and clears all gameplay without changing the city (15.6306ms)
✔ versioned save round trip restores mode, position, vehicle, progress and options (6.3368ms)
✔ invalid JSON, future schema, wrong seed and oversized saves are rejected (0.9777ms)
✔ schema normalizes every unsafe numeric option and only retains known fields (0.8412ms)
✔ progress lists are deduplicated and bounded without serializing AI (1.3437ms)
✔ migration pipeline requires contiguous versions and refuses unknown future data (0.4079ms)
✔ autosave batches checkpoint requests and writes periodically, never every frame (2.8438ms)
✔ localStorage denial and quota errors do not escape into the game loop (4.074ms)
✔ new game remains playable when storage methods are denied (0.7147ms)
✔ new game clears existing save and continuing does not mutate storage (0.5148ms)
✔ streaming removes and reloads actual meshes, preserving exact deterministic buffers (410.8715ms)
✔ streaming collider reload preserves blocking and does not duplicate spatial entries (304.3173ms)
✔ streaming keeps player safety ring and prioritizes predicted travel (179.3315ms)
✔ chunk generation obeys a soft per-frame budget and leaves work queued (140.1882ms)
✔ shared materials and base geometries survive chunk unload (116.8483ms)
✔ async startup reproduces synchronous city regardless of yielding order (229.5192ms)
✔ pause stops the shared simulation clock and resets the first resumed delta (0.4043ms)
✔ frame pacing uses a bounded sliding window and reports slow 1 percent honestly (0.5362ms)
✔ AUTO adjusts bounded populations slowly and leaves shared geometry unchanged (109.1494ms)
✔ material registry reuses keys and disposes adopted resources only once (1.5325ms)
✔ pool diagnostics observe existing pools without changing allocation or ownership (1.2415ms)
✔ camera motion zero leaves position and orientation unchanged and restores physical pose (0.8035ms)
✔ runtime resume restores actual physics, health, camera, vehicle and known discoveries (465.8959ms)
✔ resume in a building or below ground falls back to a validated safe point (272.1861ms)
✔ invalid saved vehicle is recovered to deterministic garage and remains usable (174.4605ms)
✔ safe driving resume restores camera mode and does not restore old velocity (148.3614ms)
✔ active foot mission rebuilds deterministic event and enemies without persisting AI (130.9772ms)
✔ active vehicle mission resumes its seeded route and minimum progress (119.2501ms)
✔ new game resets exploration progression, missions and principal vehicle (105.2037ms)
✔ paused shared clock leaves AI, player and vehicle unchanged then resumes without a jump (105.5396ms)
✔ rain is deterministic, local and reuses a single buffer across profiles (36.0386ms)
✔ rain off, zero intensity and invalid intensity safely disable drawing (1.78ms)
✔ steam sources cover manholes, alleys, industry and docks, and stay local (10.959ms)
✔ signal cycle is seeded, has all colors, and never gives crossing traffic simultaneous green (1.3917ms)
✔ cars stop at a red signal, then enter the intersection at green (12.7497ms)
✔ forty cars turn, stay out of buildings and recycle within a fixed allocation (444.3388ms)
✔ traffic trajectories are reproducible for the same seed and simulation ticks (43.0339ms)
✔ vehicles at every map corner recycle locally without overlaps on spawn (10.5675ms)
✔ distant police flash red/blue and reuse one moving light; LOW disables that light (1.1314ms)
✔ rail loop is closed, reproducible, continuously moving and has two named stations (278.011ms)
✔ pedestrians remain on sidewalks, outside obstacles and below the visible cap (150.7755ms)
✔ pedestrians spawn safely after relocation into every district, including waterfront (120.2346ms)
✔ steam sources and particle positions repeat exactly for a seed (3.5074ms)
✔ window groups contain lit and dark panes, repeat exactly, and vary in tint (2.5578ms)
✔ quality budgets are bounded; frame statistics include all draw calls (3.7176ms)
✔ audio is gesture-gated, supports all categories and clamps volume without downloads (0.4612ms)
✔ audio activates once, routes volume, replaces a category buffer and releases sources (1.0044ms)
✔ fixed-step LivingCity simulation gives the same traffic at 30 and 60 render FPS (364.583ms)
✔ arcade acceleration is progressive and identical at 30/60/120 render FPS (13.1948ms)
✔ braking first slows forward motion, then permits bounded reverse (4.6444ms)
✔ friction stops coasting and handbrake stops substantially faster (19.0985ms)
✔ steering depends on movement, supports reverse and never rotates a stopped vehicle (2.5704ms)
✔ normal and boosted maximum speeds are bounded and boost recharges (35.3141ms)
✔ vehicle control mapping respects WASD and ZQSD without consuming sprint on foot (3.2792ms)
✔ an exhausted held boost recharges without rapidly toggling until the key is released (3.6938ms)
✔ swept vehicle collision prevents tunnelling through thin walls and causes limited damage (7.6289ms)
✔ vehicles collide with another vehicle through the local dynamic spatial index (6.0338ms)
✔ vehicle gravity settles on ground without bouncing or a frame-rate dependency (12.8957ms)
✔ vehicle damage disables propulsion without an explosion and repair is progressive (2.6551ms)
✔ garage and principal spawn are reproducible and preserve all 64 chunks (759.3908ms)
✔ enter and exit transfer controls cleanly and reject speed, distance and both blocked sides (154.4115ms)
✔ repair only runs in a garage while stopped and a disabled driver can leave (126.9837ms)
✔ exit never teleports through a thin barrier between the car and a clear destination (117.1215ms)
✔ vehicle camera cycles modes, respects an obstructed boom and restores original FOV (0.6271ms)
✔ police detection has a finite range, height limit and blocks behind walls (0.1685ms)
✔ pursuit states go PURSUIT to SEARCHING to LOST to NONE and never trigger in Exploration (115.46ms)
✔ pursuit budgets shrink with quality and detection uses at most one ray per sample (106.5722ms)
✔ mission routes reproduce by seed and use connected main roads (99.2745ms)
✔ target vehicle follows its predetermined route deterministically without crossing buildings (278.2464ms)
✔ police route replanning preserves forward progress between intersections (82.5449ms)
✔ all six driving objectives validate conditions and timeout failures (497.8506ms)
✔ traffic stops for a drivable vehicle and contains four civilian categories (68.3277ms)
✔ procedural vehicle audio uses a bounded set of sources and releases all of them (0.4777ms)
✔ gravity lands on ground and remains grounded without drift (10.0968ms)
✔ one jump per press, no air jump, identical at 30/60/120 FPS (15.9ms)
✔ crouch preserves feet and standing is blocked under a low ceiling (1.9155ms)
✔ jump hits ceilings, fall lands on an elevated platform (14.6417ms)
✔ curbs and low mantles pass; tall walls cannot be climbed (6.6051ms)
✔ horizontal travel and falling do not depend on render frequency (7.7594ms)
✔ collision broad phase only includes nearby height bands and cells (1.5459ms)
✔ seed selects 25% roofs, eight deterministic interiors and six types (16.7761ms)
✔ door states, animation, locked door and occupant-safe closing (0.6738ms)
✔ interaction ray only selects the closest in-range target in its domain (3.5714ms)
✔ opaque wall blocks interaction through a facade (3.0012ms)
✔ elevator closes, carries rider and opens at chosen floor across frame rates (2.5147ms)
✔ interiors are lazy, bounded to two cached rooms, with entry/exit and roof return (18.4754ms)
✔ fire escape risers are physically walkable without jump input (11.5892ms)
✔ ladder travels to both endpoints and releases normal physics (2.8173ms)
✔ grapple defaults off, only compatible elevated points inside aim/range qualify (3.4001ms)
✔ discoveries are altitude-aware and notify only once in memory (0.3544ms)
✔ underground generates lazily, connected corridors have floors and no partition across junction (5.2434ms)
✔ all vertical routes retain four districts/64 chunks and clear road centerlines (295.051ms)
✔ switchback stair landings connect four flights without jumping or clipping (35.0302ms)
✔ all accessible roof exits have capsule clearance above facade and equipment (151.7712ms)
✔ triangle averages reset between sample windows instead of accumulating (1.4316ms)
✔ both real metro stations can be reached on foot through their complete stair route (179.7147ms)
✔ seed reproduces all transforms, colors, roofs, signs and colliders (543.9909ms)
✔ spawn and road centers remain clear, buildings and boundaries block movement (11.2151ms)
✔ running into a facade stops outside it even with long update steps (12.3282ms)
✔ W and Z move forward equally; diagonal speed stays normalized (2.7363ms)
✔ unlocked controls stop movement and reset clears held keys (0.3802ms)
✔ chunks reproduce independently of load order and detach without owning shared resources (14.5694ms)
✔ all district road networks and boundaries remain connected and traversable (38.7109ms)
✔ districts have distinct heights, all building styles and all roof details (0.9046ms)
✔ three unique landmarks are tall and have a clear street approach (0.2984ms)
✔ water, containers and crane feet block movement; old-town alleys reach plazas (1.5903ms)
✔ A/Q strafe equivalently, sprint is faster and wall sliding works (1.0334ms)
✔ geometry shares at most nine materials and every instance transform is finite (17.5754ms)
ℹ tests 185
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 185
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 2821.0896
