
> world-polish-and-persistence@7.0.0 test
> node --test tests/*.test.js

✔ grapple ray selects only marked points inside configurable range (2.3369ms)
✔ grapple pull and released momentum are identical at 30/60/120 FPS (18.7326ms)
✔ grapple cannot select through a wall or pull through a newly blocking wall (4.7717ms)
✔ grapple cancellation releases bounded velocity and permits reuse after cooldown (2.4141ms)
✔ glide reduces descent, advances and exits when Space is released (8.0271ms)
✔ glide is excluded on ground, inside rooms and during ladder travel (1.374ms)
✔ glide trajectory is independent of render frequency (6.7693ms)
✔ momentum strictly bounds horizontal and vertical velocities (2.0125ms)
✔ dodge has a bounded duration/distance, cooldown and respects walls (1.6953ms)
✔ crime site generation is deterministic, chunk-based and offers alternate approaches (10.6187ms)
✔ crime spawning avoids the player, honors budgets and recycles resolved events (10.4158ms)
✔ mission activation is exclusive and reach/roof/inspect/enter objectives complete (0.7203ms)
✔ observation requires sustained aim; neutralization requires a real disabled group (0.7969ms)
✔ missions fail on expiration or removal of their event (0.4672ms)
✔ enemy vision respects cone, height, occlusion and a small rain penalty (2.1783ms)
✔ enemy transitions from suspicion to alert, search and patrol; disabled is terminal (0.7749ms)
✔ noise is bounded, expires, respects range and is slightly masked by rain (0.4051ms)
✔ hearing creates suspicion without immediately alerting the enemy (0.2126ms)
✔ takedown requires short distance, rear approach, no wall and non-alert enemy (1.0654ms)
✔ combat takes three hits, enforces cooldown, range and line of sight (2.8107ms)
✔ health clamps damage, saves safe point and respawns once after a fixed delay (0.7899ms)
✔ scanner has a limited duration, radius and cooldown and reveals nothing when disabled (0.2963ms)
✔ AI perception is staggered to at most two vision rays per simulation tick (10.8687ms)
✔ exploration/vigilante switch enables and clears all gameplay without changing the city (11.3311ms)
✔ versioned save round trip restores mode, position, vehicle, progress and options (4.3798ms)
✔ invalid JSON, future schema, wrong seed and oversized saves are rejected (0.7767ms)
✔ schema normalizes every unsafe numeric option and only retains known fields (0.3528ms)
✔ progress lists are deduplicated and bounded without serializing AI (0.7123ms)
✔ migration pipeline requires contiguous versions and refuses unknown future data (0.3071ms)
✔ autosave batches checkpoint requests and writes periodically, never every frame (1.1741ms)
✔ localStorage denial and quota errors do not escape into the game loop (0.7834ms)
✔ new game remains playable when storage methods are denied (0.4748ms)
✔ new game clears existing save and continuing does not mutate storage (2.1151ms)
✔ streaming removes and reloads actual meshes, preserving exact deterministic buffers (198.8845ms)
✔ streaming collider reload preserves blocking and does not duplicate spatial entries (142.5042ms)
✔ streaming keeps player safety ring and prioritizes predicted travel (116.6658ms)
✔ chunk generation obeys a soft per-frame budget and leaves work queued (80.8209ms)
✔ shared materials and base geometries survive chunk unload (74.758ms)
✔ async startup reproduces synchronous city regardless of yielding order (167.8401ms)
✔ pause stops the shared simulation clock and resets the first resumed delta (0.38ms)
✔ frame pacing uses a bounded sliding window and reports slow 1 percent honestly (1.1843ms)
✔ AUTO adjusts bounded populations slowly and leaves shared geometry unchanged (67.5488ms)
✔ material registry reuses keys and disposes adopted resources only once (0.2244ms)
✔ pool diagnostics observe existing pools without changing allocation or ownership (0.3668ms)
✔ camera motion zero leaves position and orientation unchanged and restores physical pose (1.6757ms)
✔ runtime resume restores actual physics, health, camera, vehicle and known discoveries (219.4565ms)
✔ resume in a building or below ground falls back to a validated safe point (146.212ms)
✔ invalid saved vehicle is recovered to deterministic garage and remains usable (107.3765ms)
✔ safe driving resume restores camera mode and does not restore old velocity (90.0756ms)
✔ active foot mission rebuilds deterministic event and enemies without persisting AI (88.2585ms)
✔ active vehicle mission resumes its seeded route and minimum progress (89.3666ms)
✔ new game resets exploration progression, missions and principal vehicle (76.1349ms)
✔ paused shared clock leaves AI, player and vehicle unchanged then resumes without a jump (78.9712ms)
✔ rain is deterministic, local and reuses a single buffer across profiles (16.1494ms)
✔ rain off, zero intensity and invalid intensity safely disable drawing (1.2405ms)
✔ steam sources cover manholes, alleys, industry and docks, and stay local (19.7355ms)
✔ signal cycle is seeded, has all colors, and never gives crossing traffic simultaneous green (1.3306ms)
✔ cars stop at a red signal, then enter the intersection at green (8.7663ms)
✔ forty cars turn, stay out of buildings and recycle within a fixed allocation (298.4101ms)
✔ traffic trajectories are reproducible for the same seed and simulation ticks (28.0929ms)
✔ vehicles at every map corner recycle locally without overlaps on spawn (8.7844ms)
✔ distant police flash red/blue and reuse one moving light; LOW disables that light (1.0109ms)
✔ rail loop is closed, reproducible, continuously moving and has two named stations (188.0884ms)
✔ pedestrians remain on sidewalks, outside obstacles and below the visible cap (118.4573ms)
✔ pedestrians spawn safely after relocation into every district, including waterfront (85.6062ms)
✔ steam sources and particle positions repeat exactly for a seed (4.6596ms)
✔ window groups contain lit and dark panes, repeat exactly, and vary in tint (1.9293ms)
✔ quality budgets are bounded; frame statistics include all draw calls (2.1644ms)
✔ audio is gesture-gated, supports all categories and clamps volume without downloads (0.4169ms)
✔ audio activates once, routes volume, replaces a category buffer and releases sources (1.0723ms)
✔ fixed-step LivingCity simulation gives the same traffic at 30 and 60 render FPS (272.4547ms)
✔ arcade acceleration is progressive and identical at 30/60/120 render FPS (11.7743ms)
✔ braking first slows forward motion, then permits bounded reverse (2.1679ms)
✔ friction stops coasting and handbrake stops substantially faster (14.289ms)
✔ steering depends on movement, supports reverse and never rotates a stopped vehicle (1.5918ms)
✔ normal and boosted maximum speeds are bounded and boost recharges (15.9209ms)
✔ vehicle control mapping respects WASD and ZQSD without consuming sprint on foot (2.6379ms)
✔ an exhausted held boost recharges without rapidly toggling until the key is released (2.2186ms)
✔ swept vehicle collision prevents tunnelling through thin walls and causes limited damage (5.1887ms)
✔ vehicles collide with another vehicle through the local dynamic spatial index (6.0835ms)
✔ vehicle gravity settles on ground without bouncing or a frame-rate dependency (6.1753ms)
✔ vehicle damage disables propulsion without an explosion and repair is progressive (1.3201ms)
✔ garage and principal spawn are reproducible and preserve all 64 chunks (446.4445ms)
✔ enter and exit transfer controls cleanly and reject speed, distance and both blocked sides (104.2797ms)
✔ repair only runs in a garage while stopped and a disabled driver can leave (95.4151ms)
✔ exit never teleports through a thin barrier between the car and a clear destination (87.819ms)
✔ vehicle camera cycles modes, respects an obstructed boom and restores original FOV (0.7595ms)
✔ police detection has a finite range, height limit and blocks behind walls (0.236ms)
✔ pursuit states go PURSUIT to SEARCHING to LOST to NONE and never trigger in Exploration (108.8741ms)
✔ pursuit budgets shrink with quality and detection uses at most one ray per sample (75.1194ms)
✔ mission routes reproduce by seed and use connected main roads (71.0375ms)
✔ target vehicle follows its predetermined route deterministically without crossing buildings (200.2109ms)
✔ police route replanning preserves forward progress between intersections (52.5306ms)
✔ all six driving objectives validate conditions and timeout failures (361.4767ms)
✔ traffic stops for a drivable vehicle and contains four civilian categories (52.2209ms)
✔ procedural vehicle audio uses a bounded set of sources and releases all of them (0.5061ms)
✔ gravity lands on ground and remains grounded without drift (7.9442ms)
✔ one jump per press, no air jump, identical at 30/60/120 FPS (8.8322ms)
✔ crouch preserves feet and standing is blocked under a low ceiling (2.4751ms)
✔ jump hits ceilings, fall lands on an elevated platform (3.594ms)
✔ curbs and low mantles pass; tall walls cannot be climbed (5.5548ms)
✔ horizontal travel and falling do not depend on render frequency (3.5612ms)
✔ collision broad phase only includes nearby height bands and cells (1.6143ms)
✔ seed selects 25% roofs, eight deterministic interiors and six types (10.4932ms)
✔ door states, animation, locked door and occupant-safe closing (0.8705ms)
✔ interaction ray only selects the closest in-range target in its domain (1.8535ms)
✔ opaque wall blocks interaction through a facade (0.711ms)
✔ elevator closes, carries rider and opens at chosen floor across frame rates (2.0909ms)
✔ interiors are lazy, bounded to two cached rooms, with entry/exit and roof return (19.5831ms)
✔ fire escape risers are physically walkable without jump input (10.2345ms)
✔ ladder travels to both endpoints and releases normal physics (2.1981ms)
✔ grapple defaults off, only compatible elevated points inside aim/range qualify (1.282ms)
✔ discoveries are altitude-aware and notify only once in memory (0.2778ms)
✔ underground generates lazily, connected corridors have floors and no partition across junction (4.3733ms)
✔ all vertical routes retain four districts/64 chunks and clear road centerlines (154.2158ms)
✔ switchback stair landings connect four flights without jumping or clipping (28.3428ms)
✔ all accessible roof exits have capsule clearance above facade and equipment (98.7769ms)
✔ triangle averages reset between sample windows instead of accumulating (0.4194ms)
✔ both real metro stations can be reached on foot through their complete stair route (135.7933ms)
✔ seed reproduces all transforms, colors, roofs, signs and colliders (292.242ms)
✔ spawn and road centers remain clear, buildings and boundaries block movement (7.6851ms)
✔ running into a facade stops outside it even with long update steps (13.1964ms)
✔ W and Z move forward equally; diagonal speed stays normalized (2.114ms)
✔ unlocked controls stop movement and reset clears held keys (1.0306ms)
✔ chunks reproduce independently of load order and detach without owning shared resources (11.4577ms)
✔ all district road networks and boundaries remain connected and traversable (54.7987ms)
✔ districts have distinct heights, all building styles and all roof details (2.0959ms)
✔ three unique landmarks are tall and have a clear street approach (0.8482ms)
✔ water, containers and crane feet block movement; old-town alleys reach plazas (3.4827ms)
✔ A/Q strafe equivalently, sprint is faster and wall sliding works (0.9971ms)
✔ geometry shares at most nine materials and every instance transform is finite (12.6438ms)
ℹ tests 131
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 131
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 2308.3111
