
> playtest-and-release-candidate@0.10.0 test
> node --test tests/*.test.js

✔ four district art profiles carry unique palette, use and silhouette rules (1.5819ms)
✔ district mixing is normalized and continuous across both axes (0.5986ms)
✔ skyline peaks in downtown and preserves low docks and industrial hierarchy (0.3678ms)
✔ facade palette, material variation and window family reproduce exactly (1.2234ms)
✔ all silhouette sections fit their parcel and the final roof remains centered (2.1662ms)
✔ fictional signs have deterministic names and a strictly bounded catalogue (14.9619ms)
✔ V3 windows offer four colors while retaining the historical window API (2.9762ms)
✔ distance bands and budgets are nested from LOW to HIGH (0.2672ms)
✔ prop LOD hides complete props without changing transforms or colors (1.7195ms)
✔ graphics changes do not modify generated identities (269.7541ms)
✔ street props use repeatable recipes clear of existing solid envelopes (157.0574ms)
✔ decorations unload, restore art metadata and reproduce exact instance data (159.2506ms)
✔ material count is bounded and all mineral surfaces share procedural shader variants (103.8776ms)
✔ fixed instance pool is reused and enforces its hard limit (1.0484ms)
✔ fog has continuous district transitions, altitude thinning and rain thickening (0.4423ms)
✔ rain perception varies smoothly and is reduced for driving (0.2136ms)
✔ rain splash pool is bounded, profile controlled and disabled with rain (8.0231ms)
✔ rare storms repeat on the seed, never fire every minute, and respect pause (1.2871ms)
✔ storm toggle suppresses flash and pending thunder (0.2086ms)
✔ new visual options round trip and older saves receive harmless defaults (0.4376ms)
✔ AUTO reduces art gradually without changing seed or buffers (74.1606ms)
✔ far windows replace detailed panes and reduce the drawn instance count (84.988ms)
✔ streaming created after LOW retains the full HIGH decoration allocation (83.9247ms)
✔ offset wings have matching physical volumes rather than centered phantom walls (76.1184ms)
✔ shader warmup restores lights, target and interaction owners (73.4619ms)
✔ shader warmup restores lights, target and interaction owners after failure (61.6587ms)
✔ authored locations, objectives, road widths and rooftop chain are physically valid (51.0656ms)
✔ main mission identities and positions stay fixed across secondary seeds (2.2938ms)
✔ campaign prerequisites cannot be bypassed by starting a locked mission (1.4236ms)
✔ all main routes have distinct playable access objectives (1.18ms)
✔ each mission walkthrough resumes every checkpoint and completes once (2.0887ms)
✔ all seven campaign missions complete, reward and unlock their successor (2.6593ms)
✔ side replay never grants duplicate points or lore (1.3175ms)
✔ objective evidence requires the right domain, action and traversal (1.3568ms)
✔ real inspect interaction advances the active objective only in its interior (3.8152ms)
✔ checkpoint restart retains progress; mission restart returns to the beginning (2.2414ms)
✔ KO returns to the last authored checkpoint without losing discoveries (3.1604ms)
✔ content pause freezes objective and radio timers (3.3924ms)
✔ Exploration suspends story and requires opt-in for discoveries (2.1983ms)
✔ undiscovered secrets and lore never appear as direct map markers (1.3553ms)
✔ nearby secret is collected through real interaction and saved (1.5224ms)
✔ fast travel requires discovery and rejects pursuit, combat and active missions (1.2707ms)
✔ safe point travel prepares its chunk and places a grounded destination (0.9935ms)
✔ fast travel from a moving vehicle exits cleanly and parks it (1.2394ms)
✔ six upgrades enforce point costs, bounds and no duplicate purchase (1.1098ms)
✔ upgrade restore cannot spend more than earned or stack repeated bonuses (1.0002ms)
✔ V1 migration preserves player, vehicle, settings and historical progress (1.6249ms)
✔ runtime save round trip retains checkpoint, lore, safe points and upgrades (9.1059ms)
✔ new game removes authored progression but retains user options (2.0383ms)
✔ malformed content is bounded and multiple active missions normalize to one (0.9338ms)
✔ radio queue is bounded, pauses and releases its current line (0.7939ms)
✔ world events are rare, singular, pause aware and restore rain (0.7921ms)
✔ content decoration buffers stay bounded through zones and profiles (4.3109ms)
✔ mission encounters reuse the existing enemy pool and clear on restart (3.7506ms)
✔ grapple ray selects only marked points inside configurable range (2.0056ms)
✔ grapple pull and released momentum are identical at 30/60/120 FPS (19.3009ms)
✔ grapple cannot select through a wall or pull through a newly blocking wall (5.8908ms)
✔ grapple cancellation releases bounded velocity and permits reuse after cooldown (4.3589ms)
✔ glide reduces descent, advances and exits when Space is released (5.435ms)
✔ glide is excluded on ground, inside rooms and during ladder travel (2.3632ms)
✔ glide trajectory is independent of render frequency (5.1211ms)
✔ momentum strictly bounds horizontal and vertical velocities (1.3839ms)
✔ dodge has a bounded duration/distance, cooldown and respects walls (2.3485ms)
✔ crime site generation is deterministic, chunk-based and offers alternate approaches (11.3839ms)
✔ crime spawning avoids the player, honors budgets and recycles resolved events (6.1294ms)
✔ mission activation is exclusive and reach/roof/inspect/enter objectives complete (0.4991ms)
✔ observation requires sustained aim; neutralization requires a real disabled group (0.8031ms)
✔ missions fail on expiration or removal of their event (0.3106ms)
✔ enemy vision respects cone, height, occlusion and a small rain penalty (1.1024ms)
✔ enemy transitions from suspicion to alert, search and patrol; disabled is terminal (0.2297ms)
✔ noise is bounded, expires, respects range and is slightly masked by rain (0.4326ms)
✔ hearing creates suspicion without immediately alerting the enemy (0.1941ms)
✔ takedown requires short distance, rear approach, no wall and non-alert enemy (1.3543ms)
✔ combat takes three hits, enforces cooldown, range and line of sight (1.767ms)
✔ health clamps damage, saves safe point and respawns once after a fixed delay (0.4791ms)
✔ scanner has a limited duration, radius and cooldown and reveals nothing when disabled (0.2493ms)
✔ AI perception is staggered to at most two vision rays per simulation tick (5.5342ms)
✔ exploration/vigilante switch enables and clears all gameplay without changing the city (12.2453ms)
✔ versioned save round trip restores mode, position, vehicle, progress and options (4.3493ms)
✔ invalid JSON, future schema, wrong seed and oversized saves are rejected (0.4929ms)
✔ schema normalizes every unsafe numeric option and only retains known fields (0.373ms)
✔ progress lists are deduplicated and bounded without serializing AI (0.6668ms)
✔ migration pipeline requires contiguous versions and refuses unknown future data (0.3188ms)
✔ autosave batches checkpoint requests and writes periodically, never every frame (2.4927ms)
✔ localStorage denial and quota errors do not escape into the game loop (0.5893ms)
✔ new game remains playable when storage methods are denied (1.738ms)
✔ new game clears existing save and continuing does not mutate storage (0.3783ms)
✔ streaming removes and reloads actual meshes, preserving exact deterministic buffers (279.4757ms)
✔ streaming collider reload preserves blocking and does not duplicate spatial entries (170.6926ms)
✔ streaming keeps player safety ring and prioritizes predicted travel (125.0873ms)
✔ chunk generation obeys a soft per-frame budget and leaves work queued (103.5214ms)
✔ shared materials and base geometries survive chunk unload (81.1463ms)
✔ async startup reproduces synchronous city regardless of yielding order (162.6741ms)
✔ pause stops the shared simulation clock and resets the first resumed delta (0.3186ms)
✔ frame pacing uses a bounded sliding window and reports slow 1 percent honestly (0.3732ms)
✔ AUTO adjusts bounded populations slowly and leaves shared geometry unchanged (76.7984ms)
✔ material registry reuses keys and disposes adopted resources only once (0.2023ms)
✔ pool diagnostics observe existing pools without changing allocation or ownership (0.314ms)
✔ camera motion zero leaves position and orientation unchanged and restores physical pose (0.6797ms)
✔ V10 keeps save schema 2 and semantic release version (4.8714ms)
✔ tutorial appears once, survives restore and new game resets it (8.5547ms)
✔ tutorial preferences suppress nonessential or all prompts (1.2719ms)
✔ Exploration never introduces combat, scanner or grapple tutorials (5.136ms)
✔ tutorial timers remain paused (1.7989ms)
✔ backup retains previous valid generation and restores corrupt primary (6.3106ms)
✔ unknown versions and invalid JSON fall back without deleting either save (2.3249ms)
✔ nonfinite and out-of-world values recover, unknown content IDs are ignored (2.3636ms)
✔ 100 actual save/load cycles preserve content, vehicle, position and preferences (109.4429ms)
✔ campaign completes through runtime actions, unlocks and reloads all seven missions (89.7687ms)
✔ replayed mission cannot duplicate a reward and upgrade cannot be bought twice (2.9785ms)
✔ failure prepares checkpoint and offers restart or free roam without a reload (1.1028ms)
✔ vehicle recovery restores the same instance and refuses pursuit or critical mission (1.5803ms)
✔ stuck detection proposes reposition only after sustained throttle and consent (2.8422ms)
✔ fast travel leaves one vehicle instance across indoor, underground and rainy routes (3.473ms)
✔ input actions have no same-context conflicts; V and Space are contextual (0.8834ms)
✔ frame spike counters expire on the rolling window (0.8422ms)
✔ CPU profiler records a finite bounded key per subsystem (0.5495ms)
✔ zero camera motion suppresses bob, damage, landing and boost offsets (0.7318ms)
✔ reduce flashes suppresses lightning exposure while retaining grading (0.4595ms)
✔ enemy suspicion takes time and searching expires after loss of contact (0.378ms)
✔ enemy vision cannot pass a solid wall (0.8251ms)
✔ new game remains resumable if pointer lock has not been granted (0.6059ms)
✔ quota failure while writing backup leaves primary save intact (0.6957ms)
✔ chunk failure is logged once, keeps collisions and stops retrying until reload (3.4058ms)
✔ runtime resume restores actual physics, health, camera, vehicle and known discoveries (287.6681ms)
✔ resume in a building or below ground falls back to a validated safe point (159.5938ms)
✔ invalid saved vehicle is recovered to deterministic garage and remains usable (136.4684ms)
✔ safe driving resume restores camera mode and does not restore old velocity (104.3129ms)
✔ active foot mission rebuilds deterministic event and enemies without persisting AI (76.0598ms)
✔ active vehicle mission resumes its seeded route and minimum progress (90.798ms)
✔ new game resets exploration progression, missions and principal vehicle (84.622ms)
✔ paused shared clock leaves AI, player and vehicle unchanged then resumes without a jump (81.5389ms)
✔ rain is deterministic, local and reuses a single buffer across profiles (15.2259ms)
✔ rain off, zero intensity and invalid intensity safely disable drawing (1.6196ms)
✔ steam sources cover manholes, alleys, industry and docks, and stay local (7.206ms)
✔ signal cycle is seeded, has all colors, and never gives crossing traffic simultaneous green (1.1395ms)
✔ cars stop at a red signal, then enter the intersection at green (7.0332ms)
✔ forty cars turn, stay out of buildings and recycle within a fixed allocation (277.6919ms)
✔ traffic trajectories are reproducible for the same seed and simulation ticks (29.0622ms)
✔ vehicles at every map corner recycle locally without overlaps on spawn (5.601ms)
✔ distant police flash red/blue and reuse one moving light; LOW disables that light (0.8452ms)
✔ rail loop is closed, reproducible, continuously moving and has two named stations (192.9454ms)
✔ pedestrians remain on sidewalks, outside obstacles and below the visible cap (118.0959ms)
✔ pedestrians spawn safely after relocation into every district, including waterfront (87.9837ms)
✔ steam sources and particle positions repeat exactly for a seed (3.5424ms)
✔ window groups contain lit and dark panes, repeat exactly, and vary in tint (2.2466ms)
✔ quality budgets are bounded; frame statistics include all draw calls (2.946ms)
✔ audio is gesture-gated, supports all categories and clamps volume without downloads (0.451ms)
✔ audio activates once, routes volume, replaces a category buffer and releases sources (1.0027ms)
✔ fixed-step LivingCity simulation gives the same traffic at 30 and 60 render FPS (260.7876ms)
✔ arcade acceleration is progressive and identical at 30/60/120 render FPS (10.2387ms)
✔ braking first slows forward motion, then permits bounded reverse (2.7035ms)
✔ friction stops coasting and handbrake stops substantially faster (11.8241ms)
✔ steering depends on movement, supports reverse and never rotates a stopped vehicle (1.6693ms)
✔ normal and boosted maximum speeds are bounded and boost recharges (16.0822ms)
✔ vehicle control mapping respects WASD and ZQSD without consuming sprint on foot (1.2784ms)
✔ an exhausted held boost recharges without rapidly toggling until the key is released (3.0607ms)
✔ swept vehicle collision prevents tunnelling through thin walls and causes limited damage (5.6498ms)
✔ vehicles collide with another vehicle through the local dynamic spatial index (3.8328ms)
✔ vehicle gravity settles on ground without bouncing or a frame-rate dependency (9.6125ms)
✔ vehicle damage disables propulsion without an explosion and repair is progressive (5.836ms)
✔ garage and principal spawn are reproducible and preserve all 64 chunks (524.6702ms)
✔ enter and exit transfer controls cleanly and reject speed, distance and both blocked sides (105.0031ms)
✔ repair only runs in a garage while stopped and a disabled driver can leave (96.3223ms)
✔ exit never teleports through a thin barrier between the car and a clear destination (95.4897ms)
✔ vehicle camera cycles modes, respects an obstructed boom and restores original FOV (0.4805ms)
✔ police detection has a finite range, height limit and blocks behind walls (0.1761ms)
✔ pursuit states go PURSUIT to SEARCHING to LOST to NONE and never trigger in Exploration (92.1773ms)
✔ pursuit budgets shrink with quality and detection uses at most one ray per sample (72.1487ms)
✔ mission routes reproduce by seed and use connected main roads (65.4374ms)
✔ target vehicle follows its predetermined route deterministically without crossing buildings (193.7324ms)
✔ police route replanning preserves forward progress between intersections (56.7949ms)
✔ all six driving objectives validate conditions and timeout failures (405.788ms)
✔ traffic stops for a drivable vehicle and contains four civilian categories (62.8253ms)
✔ procedural vehicle audio uses a bounded set of sources and releases all of them (0.731ms)
✔ gravity lands on ground and remains grounded without drift (9.0895ms)
✔ one jump per press, no air jump, identical at 30/60/120 FPS (8.5446ms)
✔ crouch preserves feet and standing is blocked under a low ceiling (5.7145ms)
✔ jump hits ceilings, fall lands on an elevated platform (5.5398ms)
✔ curbs and low mantles pass; tall walls cannot be climbed (5.1893ms)
✔ horizontal travel and falling do not depend on render frequency (4.6803ms)
✔ collision broad phase only includes nearby height bands and cells (1.0172ms)
✔ seed selects 25% roofs, eight deterministic interiors and six types (7.3369ms)
✔ door states, animation, locked door and occupant-safe closing (0.7347ms)
✔ interaction ray only selects the closest in-range target in its domain (1.9367ms)
✔ opaque wall blocks interaction through a facade (0.9072ms)
✔ elevator closes, carries rider and opens at chosen floor across frame rates (1.5996ms)
✔ interiors are lazy, bounded to two cached rooms, with entry/exit and roof return (16.0665ms)
✔ fire escape risers are physically walkable without jump input (6.0644ms)
✔ ladder travels to both endpoints and releases normal physics (2.68ms)
✔ grapple defaults off, only compatible elevated points inside aim/range qualify (2.7512ms)
✔ discoveries are altitude-aware and notify only once in memory (0.2782ms)
✔ underground generates lazily, connected corridors have floors and no partition across junction (3.6595ms)
✔ all vertical routes retain four districts/64 chunks and clear road centerlines (181.0358ms)
✔ switchback stair landings connect four flights without jumping or clipping (23.0183ms)
✔ all accessible roof exits have capsule clearance above facade and equipment (111.0217ms)
✔ triangle averages reset between sample windows instead of accumulating (0.3056ms)
✔ both real metro stations can be reached on foot through their complete stair route (125.6995ms)
✔ seed reproduces all transforms, colors, roofs, signs and colliders (327.236ms)
✔ spawn and road centers remain clear, buildings and boundaries block movement (5.8361ms)
✔ running into a facade stops outside it even with long update steps (10.9558ms)
✔ W and Z move forward equally; diagonal speed stays normalized (1.246ms)
✔ unlocked controls stop movement and reset clears held keys (0.3402ms)
✔ chunks reproduce independently of load order and detach without owning shared resources (11.7751ms)
✔ all district road networks and boundaries remain connected and traversable (31.9599ms)
✔ districts have distinct heights, all building styles and all roof details (0.6254ms)
✔ three unique landmarks are tall and have a clear street approach (0.2583ms)
✔ water, containers and crane feet block movement; old-town alleys reach plazas (1.3808ms)
✔ A/Q strafe equivalently, sprint is faster and wall sliding works (0.5811ms)
✔ geometry shares at most nine materials and every instance transform is finite (14.0046ms)
ℹ tests 210
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 210
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 2058.3095
