
> content-and-level-design@9.0.0 test
> node --test tests/*.test.js

✔ four district art profiles carry unique palette, use and silhouette rules (1.4559ms)
✔ district mixing is normalized and continuous across both axes (0.3958ms)
✔ skyline peaks in downtown and preserves low docks and industrial hierarchy (0.2845ms)
✔ facade palette, material variation and window family reproduce exactly (1.0458ms)
✔ all silhouette sections fit their parcel and the final roof remains centered (2.0837ms)
✔ fictional signs have deterministic names and a strictly bounded catalogue (13.3106ms)
✔ V3 windows offer four colors while retaining the historical window API (2.8306ms)
✔ distance bands and budgets are nested from LOW to HIGH (0.3005ms)
✔ prop LOD hides complete props without changing transforms or colors (1.2054ms)
✔ graphics changes do not modify generated identities (230.8273ms)
✔ street props use repeatable recipes clear of existing solid envelopes (158.9471ms)
✔ decorations unload, restore art metadata and reproduce exact instance data (153.2582ms)
✔ material count is bounded and all mineral surfaces share procedural shader variants (94.0045ms)
✔ fixed instance pool is reused and enforces its hard limit (0.8047ms)
✔ fog has continuous district transitions, altitude thinning and rain thickening (0.2882ms)
✔ rain perception varies smoothly and is reduced for driving (0.2774ms)
✔ rain splash pool is bounded, profile controlled and disabled with rain (6.6339ms)
✔ rare storms repeat on the seed, never fire every minute, and respect pause (1.1331ms)
✔ storm toggle suppresses flash and pending thunder (0.2045ms)
✔ new visual options round trip and older saves receive harmless defaults (0.4223ms)
✔ AUTO reduces art gradually without changing seed or buffers (87.5487ms)
✔ far windows replace detailed panes and reduce the drawn instance count (81.4914ms)
✔ streaming created after LOW retains the full HIGH decoration allocation (83.019ms)
✔ offset wings have matching physical volumes rather than centered phantom walls (71.4986ms)
✔ shader warmup restores lights, target and interaction owners (67.015ms)
✔ shader warmup restores lights, target and interaction owners after failure (61.8008ms)
✔ authored locations, objectives, road widths and rooftop chain are physically valid (62.1325ms)
✔ main mission identities and positions stay fixed across secondary seeds (4.0905ms)
✔ campaign prerequisites cannot be bypassed by starting a locked mission (1.8172ms)
✔ all main routes have distinct playable access objectives (1.9494ms)
✔ each mission walkthrough resumes every checkpoint and completes once (3.3193ms)
✔ all seven campaign missions complete, reward and unlock their successor (1.6885ms)
✔ side replay never grants duplicate points or lore (1.509ms)
✔ objective evidence requires the right domain, action and traversal (1.0324ms)
✔ real inspect interaction advances the active objective only in its interior (3.4693ms)
✔ checkpoint restart retains progress; mission restart returns to the beginning (2.9086ms)
✔ KO returns to the last authored checkpoint without losing discoveries (2.4632ms)
✔ content pause freezes objective and radio timers (3.2117ms)
✔ Exploration suspends story and requires opt-in for discoveries (2.1821ms)
✔ undiscovered secrets and lore never appear as direct map markers (0.9735ms)
✔ nearby secret is collected through real interaction and saved (1.3943ms)
✔ fast travel requires discovery and rejects pursuit, combat and active missions (1.1339ms)
✔ safe point travel prepares its chunk and places a grounded destination (1.8142ms)
✔ fast travel from a moving vehicle exits cleanly and parks it (2.6876ms)
✔ six upgrades enforce point costs, bounds and no duplicate purchase (1.2598ms)
✔ upgrade restore cannot spend more than earned or stack repeated bonuses (1.0255ms)
✔ V1 migration preserves player, vehicle, settings and historical progress (1.7799ms)
✔ runtime save round trip retains checkpoint, lore, safe points and upgrades (4.3287ms)
✔ new game removes authored progression but retains user options (1.8584ms)
✔ malformed content is bounded and multiple active missions normalize to one (0.9981ms)
✔ radio queue is bounded, pauses and releases its current line (0.8333ms)
✔ world events are rare, singular, pause aware and restore rain (0.7791ms)
✔ content decoration buffers stay bounded through zones and profiles (4.4098ms)
✔ mission encounters reuse the existing enemy pool and clear on restart (3.0739ms)
✔ grapple ray selects only marked points inside configurable range (2.0229ms)
✔ grapple pull and released momentum are identical at 30/60/120 FPS (19.5885ms)
✔ grapple cannot select through a wall or pull through a newly blocking wall (4.9243ms)
✔ grapple cancellation releases bounded velocity and permits reuse after cooldown (4.0782ms)
✔ glide reduces descent, advances and exits when Space is released (4.6485ms)
✔ glide is excluded on ground, inside rooms and during ladder travel (1.6389ms)
✔ glide trajectory is independent of render frequency (7.2161ms)
✔ momentum strictly bounds horizontal and vertical velocities (1.4188ms)
✔ dodge has a bounded duration/distance, cooldown and respects walls (2.488ms)
✔ crime site generation is deterministic, chunk-based and offers alternate approaches (10.2475ms)
✔ crime spawning avoids the player, honors budgets and recycles resolved events (5.907ms)
✔ mission activation is exclusive and reach/roof/inspect/enter objectives complete (0.5679ms)
✔ observation requires sustained aim; neutralization requires a real disabled group (0.889ms)
✔ missions fail on expiration or removal of their event (0.2662ms)
✔ enemy vision respects cone, height, occlusion and a small rain penalty (1.5591ms)
✔ enemy transitions from suspicion to alert, search and patrol; disabled is terminal (0.3756ms)
✔ noise is bounded, expires, respects range and is slightly masked by rain (0.5989ms)
✔ hearing creates suspicion without immediately alerting the enemy (0.2722ms)
✔ takedown requires short distance, rear approach, no wall and non-alert enemy (1.3461ms)
✔ combat takes three hits, enforces cooldown, range and line of sight (1.4304ms)
✔ health clamps damage, saves safe point and respawns once after a fixed delay (0.533ms)
✔ scanner has a limited duration, radius and cooldown and reveals nothing when disabled (0.3039ms)
✔ AI perception is staggered to at most two vision rays per simulation tick (4.9917ms)
✔ exploration/vigilante switch enables and clears all gameplay without changing the city (11.1369ms)
✔ versioned save round trip restores mode, position, vehicle, progress and options (3.5331ms)
✔ invalid JSON, future schema, wrong seed and oversized saves are rejected (0.3927ms)
✔ schema normalizes every unsafe numeric option and only retains known fields (0.3732ms)
✔ progress lists are deduplicated and bounded without serializing AI (0.6101ms)
✔ migration pipeline requires contiguous versions and refuses unknown future data (0.2771ms)
✔ autosave batches checkpoint requests and writes periodically, never every frame (0.9966ms)
✔ localStorage denial and quota errors do not escape into the game loop (0.4175ms)
✔ new game remains playable when storage methods are denied (0.2945ms)
✔ new game clears existing save and continuing does not mutate storage (0.3527ms)
✔ streaming removes and reloads actual meshes, preserving exact deterministic buffers (252.2675ms)
✔ streaming collider reload preserves blocking and does not duplicate spatial entries (176.5854ms)
✔ streaming keeps player safety ring and prioritizes predicted travel (124.1218ms)
✔ chunk generation obeys a soft per-frame budget and leaves work queued (84.1971ms)
✔ shared materials and base geometries survive chunk unload (77.0348ms)
✔ async startup reproduces synchronous city regardless of yielding order (149.3533ms)
✔ pause stops the shared simulation clock and resets the first resumed delta (0.3489ms)
✔ frame pacing uses a bounded sliding window and reports slow 1 percent honestly (0.4663ms)
✔ AUTO adjusts bounded populations slowly and leaves shared geometry unchanged (65.3993ms)
✔ material registry reuses keys and disposes adopted resources only once (0.216ms)
✔ pool diagnostics observe existing pools without changing allocation or ownership (0.3329ms)
✔ camera motion zero leaves position and orientation unchanged and restores physical pose (0.6825ms)
✔ runtime resume restores actual physics, health, camera, vehicle and known discoveries (266.7519ms)
✔ resume in a building or below ground falls back to a validated safe point (167.0866ms)
✔ invalid saved vehicle is recovered to deterministic garage and remains usable (129.6792ms)
✔ safe driving resume restores camera mode and does not restore old velocity (106.602ms)
✔ active foot mission rebuilds deterministic event and enemies without persisting AI (82.4414ms)
✔ active vehicle mission resumes its seeded route and minimum progress (79.3004ms)
✔ new game resets exploration progression, missions and principal vehicle (84.8204ms)
✔ paused shared clock leaves AI, player and vehicle unchanged then resumes without a jump (71.0134ms)
✔ rain is deterministic, local and reuses a single buffer across profiles (13.8507ms)
✔ rain off, zero intensity and invalid intensity safely disable drawing (1.5516ms)
✔ steam sources cover manholes, alleys, industry and docks, and stay local (9.7776ms)
✔ signal cycle is seeded, has all colors, and never gives crossing traffic simultaneous green (1.3358ms)
✔ cars stop at a red signal, then enter the intersection at green (5.3198ms)
✔ forty cars turn, stay out of buildings and recycle within a fixed allocation (271.8268ms)
✔ traffic trajectories are reproducible for the same seed and simulation ticks (25.286ms)
✔ vehicles at every map corner recycle locally without overlaps on spawn (7.277ms)
✔ distant police flash red/blue and reuse one moving light; LOW disables that light (1.386ms)
✔ rail loop is closed, reproducible, continuously moving and has two named stations (171.5783ms)
✔ pedestrians remain on sidewalks, outside obstacles and below the visible cap (101.167ms)
✔ pedestrians spawn safely after relocation into every district, including waterfront (89.2114ms)
✔ steam sources and particle positions repeat exactly for a seed (2.8773ms)
✔ window groups contain lit and dark panes, repeat exactly, and vary in tint (1.3703ms)
✔ quality budgets are bounded; frame statistics include all draw calls (1.7995ms)
✔ audio is gesture-gated, supports all categories and clamps volume without downloads (0.3117ms)
✔ audio activates once, routes volume, replaces a category buffer and releases sources (0.6843ms)
✔ fixed-step LivingCity simulation gives the same traffic at 30 and 60 render FPS (265.6932ms)
✔ arcade acceleration is progressive and identical at 30/60/120 render FPS (9.2827ms)
✔ braking first slows forward motion, then permits bounded reverse (2.8121ms)
✔ friction stops coasting and handbrake stops substantially faster (13.0252ms)
✔ steering depends on movement, supports reverse and never rotates a stopped vehicle (2.0512ms)
✔ normal and boosted maximum speeds are bounded and boost recharges (18.7ms)
✔ vehicle control mapping respects WASD and ZQSD without consuming sprint on foot (1.529ms)
✔ an exhausted held boost recharges without rapidly toggling until the key is released (3.4107ms)
✔ swept vehicle collision prevents tunnelling through thin walls and causes limited damage (5.7657ms)
✔ vehicles collide with another vehicle through the local dynamic spatial index (10.9679ms)
✔ vehicle gravity settles on ground without bouncing or a frame-rate dependency (9.4812ms)
✔ vehicle damage disables propulsion without an explosion and repair is progressive (1.9471ms)
✔ garage and principal spawn are reproducible and preserve all 64 chunks (490.7839ms)
✔ enter and exit transfer controls cleanly and reject speed, distance and both blocked sides (90.3907ms)
✔ repair only runs in a garage while stopped and a disabled driver can leave (97.1104ms)
✔ exit never teleports through a thin barrier between the car and a clear destination (77.3446ms)
✔ vehicle camera cycles modes, respects an obstructed boom and restores original FOV (0.3592ms)
✔ police detection has a finite range, height limit and blocks behind walls (0.1559ms)
✔ pursuit states go PURSUIT to SEARCHING to LOST to NONE and never trigger in Exploration (80.0796ms)
✔ pursuit budgets shrink with quality and detection uses at most one ray per sample (73.8524ms)
✔ mission routes reproduce by seed and use connected main roads (67.5355ms)
✔ target vehicle follows its predetermined route deterministically without crossing buildings (197.4608ms)
✔ police route replanning preserves forward progress between intersections (56.9049ms)
✔ all six driving objectives validate conditions and timeout failures (408.2026ms)
✔ traffic stops for a drivable vehicle and contains four civilian categories (55.9379ms)
✔ procedural vehicle audio uses a bounded set of sources and releases all of them (0.4822ms)
✔ gravity lands on ground and remains grounded without drift (4.7029ms)
✔ one jump per press, no air jump, identical at 30/60/120 FPS (8.5282ms)
✔ crouch preserves feet and standing is blocked under a low ceiling (1.3778ms)
✔ jump hits ceilings, fall lands on an elevated platform (3.2799ms)
✔ curbs and low mantles pass; tall walls cannot be climbed (4.4329ms)
✔ horizontal travel and falling do not depend on render frequency (5.5029ms)
✔ collision broad phase only includes nearby height bands and cells (1.2017ms)
✔ seed selects 25% roofs, eight deterministic interiors and six types (6.593ms)
✔ door states, animation, locked door and occupant-safe closing (0.5185ms)
✔ interaction ray only selects the closest in-range target in its domain (2.2559ms)
✔ opaque wall blocks interaction through a facade (1.1652ms)
✔ elevator closes, carries rider and opens at chosen floor across frame rates (1.6412ms)
✔ interiors are lazy, bounded to two cached rooms, with entry/exit and roof return (15.6514ms)
✔ fire escape risers are physically walkable without jump input (7.543ms)
✔ ladder travels to both endpoints and releases normal physics (2.3058ms)
✔ grapple defaults off, only compatible elevated points inside aim/range qualify (1.6017ms)
✔ discoveries are altitude-aware and notify only once in memory (0.325ms)
✔ underground generates lazily, connected corridors have floors and no partition across junction (3.7571ms)
✔ all vertical routes retain four districts/64 chunks and clear road centerlines (193.9119ms)
✔ switchback stair landings connect four flights without jumping or clipping (22.0244ms)
✔ all accessible roof exits have capsule clearance above facade and equipment (91.726ms)
✔ triangle averages reset between sample windows instead of accumulating (0.4014ms)
✔ both real metro stations can be reached on foot through their complete stair route (133.099ms)
✔ seed reproduces all transforms, colors, roofs, signs and colliders (323.1188ms)
✔ spawn and road centers remain clear, buildings and boundaries block movement (5.176ms)
✔ running into a facade stops outside it even with long update steps (8.1709ms)
✔ W and Z move forward equally; diagonal speed stays normalized (1.1133ms)
✔ unlocked controls stop movement and reset clears held keys (0.2834ms)
✔ chunks reproduce independently of load order and detach without owning shared resources (9.8271ms)
✔ all district road networks and boundaries remain connected and traversable (27.6819ms)
✔ districts have distinct heights, all building styles and all roof details (1.055ms)
✔ three unique landmarks are tall and have a clear street approach (0.3409ms)
✔ water, containers and crane feet block movement; old-town alleys reach plazas (2.3143ms)
✔ A/Q strafe equivalently, sprint is faster and wall sliding works (0.7779ms)
✔ geometry shares at most nine materials and every instance transform is finite (10.8132ms)
ℹ tests 185
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 185
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 1975.8931
