
> art-pass-and-atmosphere@8.0.0 test
> node --test tests/*.test.js

✔ four district art profiles carry unique palette, use and silhouette rules (1.7784ms)
✔ district mixing is normalized and continuous across both axes (0.4951ms)
✔ skyline peaks in downtown and preserves low docks and industrial hierarchy (0.5637ms)
✔ facade palette, material variation and window family reproduce exactly (1.9307ms)
✔ all silhouette sections fit their parcel and the final roof remains centered (3.0487ms)
✔ fictional signs have deterministic names and a strictly bounded catalogue (16.0884ms)
✔ V3 windows offer four colors while retaining the historical window API (2.9956ms)
✔ distance bands and budgets are nested from LOW to HIGH (0.321ms)
✔ prop LOD hides complete props without changing transforms or colors (1.8882ms)
✔ graphics changes do not modify generated identities (255.9125ms)
✔ street props use repeatable recipes clear of existing solid envelopes (149.3417ms)
✔ decorations unload, restore art metadata and reproduce exact instance data (152.3367ms)
✔ material count is bounded and all mineral surfaces share procedural shader variants (131.9443ms)
✔ fixed instance pool is reused and enforces its hard limit (1.006ms)
✔ fog has continuous district transitions, altitude thinning and rain thickening (0.398ms)
✔ rain perception varies smoothly and is reduced for driving (0.1961ms)
✔ rain splash pool is bounded, profile controlled and disabled with rain (7.0074ms)
✔ rare storms repeat on the seed, never fire every minute, and respect pause (1.1804ms)
✔ storm toggle suppresses flash and pending thunder (0.1637ms)
✔ new visual options round trip and older saves receive harmless defaults (0.3505ms)
✔ AUTO reduces art gradually without changing seed or buffers (88.5899ms)
✔ far windows replace detailed panes and reduce the drawn instance count (86.6905ms)
✔ streaming created after LOW retains the full HIGH decoration allocation (86.528ms)
✔ offset wings have matching physical volumes rather than centered phantom walls (93.7127ms)
✔ shader warmup restores lights, target and interaction owners (85.4201ms)
✔ shader warmup restores lights, target and interaction owners after failure (67.0254ms)
✔ grapple ray selects only marked points inside configurable range (2.6084ms)
✔ grapple pull and released momentum are identical at 30/60/120 FPS (20.2389ms)
✔ grapple cannot select through a wall or pull through a newly blocking wall (5.0108ms)
✔ grapple cancellation releases bounded velocity and permits reuse after cooldown (2.2418ms)
✔ glide reduces descent, advances and exits when Space is released (4.5993ms)
✔ glide is excluded on ground, inside rooms and during ladder travel (1.6533ms)
✔ glide trajectory is independent of render frequency (8.9293ms)
✔ momentum strictly bounds horizontal and vertical velocities (0.6198ms)
✔ dodge has a bounded duration/distance, cooldown and respects walls (1.4529ms)
✔ crime site generation is deterministic, chunk-based and offers alternate approaches (10.3324ms)
✔ crime spawning avoids the player, honors budgets and recycles resolved events (10.0923ms)
✔ mission activation is exclusive and reach/roof/inspect/enter objectives complete (0.5252ms)
✔ observation requires sustained aim; neutralization requires a real disabled group (0.6268ms)
✔ missions fail on expiration or removal of their event (0.3169ms)
✔ enemy vision respects cone, height, occlusion and a small rain penalty (1.349ms)
✔ enemy transitions from suspicion to alert, search and patrol; disabled is terminal (0.3557ms)
✔ noise is bounded, expires, respects range and is slightly masked by rain (0.3992ms)
✔ hearing creates suspicion without immediately alerting the enemy (0.1961ms)
✔ takedown requires short distance, rear approach, no wall and non-alert enemy (1.336ms)
✔ combat takes three hits, enforces cooldown, range and line of sight (1.0914ms)
✔ health clamps damage, saves safe point and respawns once after a fixed delay (0.4367ms)
✔ scanner has a limited duration, radius and cooldown and reveals nothing when disabled (0.2581ms)
✔ AI perception is staggered to at most two vision rays per simulation tick (4.7916ms)
✔ exploration/vigilante switch enables and clears all gameplay without changing the city (9.5226ms)
✔ versioned save round trip restores mode, position, vehicle, progress and options (5.7339ms)
✔ invalid JSON, future schema, wrong seed and oversized saves are rejected (0.7179ms)
✔ schema normalizes every unsafe numeric option and only retains known fields (0.3338ms)
✔ progress lists are deduplicated and bounded without serializing AI (1.5325ms)
✔ migration pipeline requires contiguous versions and refuses unknown future data (0.3063ms)
✔ autosave batches checkpoint requests and writes periodically, never every frame (1.1164ms)
✔ localStorage denial and quota errors do not escape into the game loop (0.5626ms)
✔ new game remains playable when storage methods are denied (0.3376ms)
✔ new game clears existing save and continuing does not mutate storage (0.4261ms)
✔ streaming removes and reloads actual meshes, preserving exact deterministic buffers (243.6978ms)
✔ streaming collider reload preserves blocking and does not duplicate spatial entries (155.7652ms)
✔ streaming keeps player safety ring and prioritizes predicted travel (146.4241ms)
✔ chunk generation obeys a soft per-frame budget and leaves work queued (135.1287ms)
✔ shared materials and base geometries survive chunk unload (99.1024ms)
✔ async startup reproduces synchronous city regardless of yielding order (167.8911ms)
✔ pause stops the shared simulation clock and resets the first resumed delta (0.232ms)
✔ frame pacing uses a bounded sliding window and reports slow 1 percent honestly (0.3141ms)
✔ AUTO adjusts bounded populations slowly and leaves shared geometry unchanged (74.4317ms)
✔ material registry reuses keys and disposes adopted resources only once (0.3663ms)
✔ pool diagnostics observe existing pools without changing allocation or ownership (0.3411ms)
✔ camera motion zero leaves position and orientation unchanged and restores physical pose (1.0452ms)
✔ runtime resume restores actual physics, health, camera, vehicle and known discoveries (271.6733ms)
✔ resume in a building or below ground falls back to a validated safe point (154.513ms)
✔ invalid saved vehicle is recovered to deterministic garage and remains usable (155.4702ms)
✔ safe driving resume restores camera mode and does not restore old velocity (126.4351ms)
✔ active foot mission rebuilds deterministic event and enemies without persisting AI (100.7458ms)
✔ active vehicle mission resumes its seeded route and minimum progress (92.2045ms)
✔ new game resets exploration progression, missions and principal vehicle (78.7634ms)
✔ paused shared clock leaves AI, player and vehicle unchanged then resumes without a jump (94.1136ms)
✔ rain is deterministic, local and reuses a single buffer across profiles (15.3533ms)
✔ rain off, zero intensity and invalid intensity safely disable drawing (1.426ms)
✔ steam sources cover manholes, alleys, industry and docks, and stay local (8.7266ms)
✔ signal cycle is seeded, has all colors, and never gives crossing traffic simultaneous green (2.3995ms)
✔ cars stop at a red signal, then enter the intersection at green (4.1243ms)
✔ forty cars turn, stay out of buildings and recycle within a fixed allocation (286.2949ms)
✔ traffic trajectories are reproducible for the same seed and simulation ticks (34.483ms)
✔ vehicles at every map corner recycle locally without overlaps on spawn (8.089ms)
✔ distant police flash red/blue and reuse one moving light; LOW disables that light (1.3216ms)
✔ rail loop is closed, reproducible, continuously moving and has two named stations (230.7123ms)
✔ pedestrians remain on sidewalks, outside obstacles and below the visible cap (111.3371ms)
✔ pedestrians spawn safely after relocation into every district, including waterfront (116.2457ms)
✔ steam sources and particle positions repeat exactly for a seed (3.5133ms)
✔ window groups contain lit and dark panes, repeat exactly, and vary in tint (1.3366ms)
✔ quality budgets are bounded; frame statistics include all draw calls (1.9777ms)
✔ audio is gesture-gated, supports all categories and clamps volume without downloads (0.3118ms)
✔ audio activates once, routes volume, replaces a category buffer and releases sources (0.6846ms)
✔ fixed-step LivingCity simulation gives the same traffic at 30 and 60 render FPS (287.3917ms)
✔ arcade acceleration is progressive and identical at 30/60/120 render FPS (17.0445ms)
✔ braking first slows forward motion, then permits bounded reverse (3.6945ms)
✔ friction stops coasting and handbrake stops substantially faster (18.0145ms)
✔ steering depends on movement, supports reverse and never rotates a stopped vehicle (1.6543ms)
✔ normal and boosted maximum speeds are bounded and boost recharges (19.1011ms)
✔ vehicle control mapping respects WASD and ZQSD without consuming sprint on foot (1.53ms)
✔ an exhausted held boost recharges without rapidly toggling until the key is released (2.9801ms)
✔ swept vehicle collision prevents tunnelling through thin walls and causes limited damage (9.5466ms)
✔ vehicles collide with another vehicle through the local dynamic spatial index (3.9486ms)
✔ vehicle gravity settles on ground without bouncing or a frame-rate dependency (7.8728ms)
✔ vehicle damage disables propulsion without an explosion and repair is progressive (2.4689ms)
✔ garage and principal spawn are reproducible and preserve all 64 chunks (516.6634ms)
✔ enter and exit transfer controls cleanly and reject speed, distance and both blocked sides (111.862ms)
✔ repair only runs in a garage while stopped and a disabled driver can leave (104.8767ms)
✔ exit never teleports through a thin barrier between the car and a clear destination (79.7816ms)
✔ vehicle camera cycles modes, respects an obstructed boom and restores original FOV (0.3397ms)
✔ police detection has a finite range, height limit and blocks behind walls (0.1585ms)
✔ pursuit states go PURSUIT to SEARCHING to LOST to NONE and never trigger in Exploration (103.1299ms)
✔ pursuit budgets shrink with quality and detection uses at most one ray per sample (84.5753ms)
✔ mission routes reproduce by seed and use connected main roads (80.7789ms)
✔ target vehicle follows its predetermined route deterministically without crossing buildings (208.81ms)
✔ police route replanning preserves forward progress between intersections (60.3337ms)
✔ all six driving objectives validate conditions and timeout failures (430.8947ms)
✔ traffic stops for a drivable vehicle and contains four civilian categories (56.6283ms)
✔ procedural vehicle audio uses a bounded set of sources and releases all of them (0.4806ms)
✔ gravity lands on ground and remains grounded without drift (8.9974ms)
✔ one jump per press, no air jump, identical at 30/60/120 FPS (7.2226ms)
✔ crouch preserves feet and standing is blocked under a low ceiling (2.2961ms)
✔ jump hits ceilings, fall lands on an elevated platform (4.3243ms)
✔ curbs and low mantles pass; tall walls cannot be climbed (3.7676ms)
✔ horizontal travel and falling do not depend on render frequency (3.4182ms)
✔ collision broad phase only includes nearby height bands and cells (0.7796ms)
✔ seed selects 25% roofs, eight deterministic interiors and six types (6.5736ms)
✔ door states, animation, locked door and occupant-safe closing (0.6537ms)
✔ interaction ray only selects the closest in-range target in its domain (1.9671ms)
✔ opaque wall blocks interaction through a facade (0.8687ms)
✔ elevator closes, carries rider and opens at chosen floor across frame rates (1.5138ms)
✔ interiors are lazy, bounded to two cached rooms, with entry/exit and roof return (13.7931ms)
✔ fire escape risers are physically walkable without jump input (5.6703ms)
✔ ladder travels to both endpoints and releases normal physics (1.9198ms)
✔ grapple defaults off, only compatible elevated points inside aim/range qualify (2.9484ms)
✔ discoveries are altitude-aware and notify only once in memory (0.4146ms)
✔ underground generates lazily, connected corridors have floors and no partition across junction (3.4596ms)
✔ all vertical routes retain four districts/64 chunks and clear road centerlines (197.3473ms)
✔ switchback stair landings connect four flights without jumping or clipping (24.0991ms)
✔ all accessible roof exits have capsule clearance above facade and equipment (120.8414ms)
✔ triangle averages reset between sample windows instead of accumulating (0.2978ms)
✔ both real metro stations can be reached on foot through their complete stair route (130.436ms)
✔ seed reproduces all transforms, colors, roofs, signs and colliders (319.806ms)
✔ spawn and road centers remain clear, buildings and boundaries block movement (6.6133ms)
✔ running into a facade stops outside it even with long update steps (11.9251ms)
✔ W and Z move forward equally; diagonal speed stays normalized (1.1774ms)
✔ unlocked controls stop movement and reset clears held keys (0.3294ms)
✔ chunks reproduce independently of load order and detach without owning shared resources (12.8258ms)
✔ all district road networks and boundaries remain connected and traversable (37.9744ms)
✔ districts have distinct heights, all building styles and all roof details (1.6062ms)
✔ three unique landmarks are tall and have a clear street approach (0.3715ms)
✔ water, containers and crane feet block movement; old-town alleys reach plazas (3.3253ms)
✔ A/Q strafe equivalently, sprint is faster and wall sliding works (2.0206ms)
✔ geometry shares at most nine materials and every instance transform is finite (13.4495ms)
ℹ tests 157
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 157
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 2158.5282
